On March 14, this year,
في 14 مارس لهذا العام
I posted this poster on Facebook.
قمت بعمل مشاركة علي الفيس بوك.
This is an image of me and my daughter
هذه صورة لي و لابنتي
holding the Israeli flag.
و نحن نمسك بالعلم الإسرائيلي
I will try to explain to you about the context of why
سأحاول ان اوضح لكم لماذا
and when I posted.
و متي قمت بعمل هذا الملصق.
A few days ago, I was sitting waiting
منذ بضعة أيام كنت أنتظر
on the line at the grocery store,
بالصف في بقالة
and the owner and one of the clients
و كان صاحب المحل و أحد الزبائن
were talking to each other,
يتحدثان مع بعضهم البعض
and the owner was explaining to the client
وكان صاحب المحل يوضح للزبون
that we're going to get 10,000 missiles on Israel.
بأننا سوف نطلق على 10,000 صاروخ علي اسرائيل.
And the client was saying, no, it's 10,000 a day.
وقال الزبون "لا. إنها 10,000 في اليوم."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
("10,000 missiles") This is the context. This is where we are now in Israel.
("10,000 صاروخ") هذا هو الموضوع. هذا هو مكاننا الآن في اسرائيل.
We have this war with Iran coming for 10 years now,
نحن في هذه الحرب مع إيران فيما يقرب من 10 سنوات الآن،
and we have people, you know, afraid.
والناس، كما تعلمون، خائفون.
It's like every year it's the last minute
وكأن كل عام هو الدقيقة الأخيرة
that we can do something about the war with Iran.
التي يمكن لنا فيها عمل شيء بخصوص الحرب مع إيران.
It's like, if we don't act now, it's too late forever,
كأنه إذا لم نفعل شيء الآن، فستضيع الفرصة للأبد،
for 10 years now.
لعشرة سنوات الآن.
So at some point it became, you know, to me,
لذلك في مرحلة ما اصبح، كما تعلمون، بالنسبة لي،
I'm a graphic designer, so I made posters about it
أنا مصمم جرافيك، لذلك صنعت ملصقات بخصوص ذلك
and I posted the one I just showed you before.
وشاركت الملصق الذي عرضته لكم من قبل.
Most of the time, I make posters, I post them on Facebook,
في غالب الاحيان، اصنع الملصقات، وأشاركهم علي الفيس بوك،
my friends like it, don't like it,
اصدقائي يعجبون بها، أو لا يعجبون بها،
most of the time don't like it, don't share it,
وفي أغلب الأحيان لا يعجبون بها، ولا يشاركونها،
don't nothing,
أو لا يفعلون شيئًا،
and it's another day.
وهذا يوم أخر.
So I went to sleep, and that was it for me.
لذلك ذهبت لأنام وهذا كل شيء بالنسبة لي.
And later on in the night, I woke up
ولاحقًا في تلك الليلة، استيقظت
because I'm always waking up in the night,
لأني استيقظ دائمًأ في الليل،
and I went by the computer and I see all these red dots,
وذهبت للحاسوب وكل ما رايته هو تلك النقاط الحمراء،
you know, on Facebook, which I've never seen before.
كما تعلمون، علي الفيس بوك، والتي لما أراها مطلقًا قبلًا.
(Laughter)
(صخك)
And I was like, "What's going on?"
وتعجبت "ما الذي يحدث؟"
So I come to the computer and I start looking on,
لذلك ذهبت للحاسوب وبدأت انظر اليه،
and suddenly I see many people talking to me,
وفجأًه رأيت الكتير من الناس يتكلمون معي،
most of them I don't know,
غالبيتهم لا أعرفهم،
and a few of them from Iran,
والقليل منهم من إيران،
which is -- What?
وهو ما أدهشني.
Because you have to understand,
عليكم أن تعلموا،
in Israel we don't talk with people from Iran.
نحن في اسرائيل لا نتكلم مع أحد من إيران.
We don't know people from Iran.
لا نعرف أحد من إيران.
It's like, on Facebook, you have friends only from --
علي الفيس بوك، لديك أصدقاء فقط من --
it's like your neighbors are your friends on Facebook.
كما لو يكن جيرانك هم فقط أصدقائك علي الفيس بوك.
And now people from Iran are talking to me.
والآن اشخاص من إيران يتحدثون معي.
So I start answering this girl, and she's telling me
لذلك بدأت اجيب هذه الفتاة، وهي تقول لي
she saw the poster and she asked her family to come,
أنها رأت الملصق وطلبت من اسرتها ان تأتي،
because they don't have a computer, she asked her family
لأنهم لا يملكون حاسوب، طلبت هي من أسرتها
to come to see the poster, and they're all sitting in the living room crying.
ان تأتي لتري الملصق، وجلسوا جميعًا وهم يبكون بحجرة المعيشة.
So I'm like, whoa.
وذلك جعلني أندهش.
I ask my wife to come, and I tell her, you have to see that.
طلبت من زوجتي ان تحضر، وقلت لها، عليك ان تري ذلك.
People are crying, and she came, she read the text,
إن الناس يبكون، وجاءت وقرأت الكلام المكتوب،
and she started to cry.
وأخذت في البكاء.
And everybody's crying now. (Laughter)
الجميع يبكون الآن. (ضحك)
So I don't know what to do, so my first reflex,
لم أعرف ماذا علي أن أفعل، وأول رد فعلٍ لي،
as a graphic designer, is, you know, to show everybody
كمصمم جرافك، يكون، كما تعلمون، هو أن أُري للجميع
what I'd just seen, and people started to see them
ما رأيته، وبدأ الناس بمشاهدتهم
and to share them, and that's how it started.
ومشاركتهم، ومن هنا كانت البداية.
The day after, when really it became a lot of talking,
في اليوم التالي، عندما كثر الحديث،
I said to myself, and my wife said to me,
قلت لنفسي، وقالت لي زوجتي،
I also want a poster,
أنا ايضا أريد ملصق،
so this is her. (Laughter)
هذه هي زوجتي. (ضحك)
Because it's working, put me in a poster now.
لأنها نجحت، أصنع لي ملصق الآن.
But more seriously, I was like, okay, these ones work,
ولكن فعلًا، فكرت، حسنًا، نجح هؤلاء،
but it's not just about me, it's about people from Israel
ولكن الموضوع لا يشملني وحدي، إنه يشمل شعب اسرائيل
who want to say something.
الذي لدية ما يقوله.
So I'm going to shoot all the people I know, if they want,
لذلك سأقوم بتصوير كل الأشخاص الذين أعرفهم، إذا أرادوا،
and I'm going to put them in a poster and I'm going to share them.
وسأضعهم في ملصق و سوف أقوم بمشاركتهم.
So I went to my neighbors and friends and students
لذلك ذهبت إلي جيراني وأصدقائي وطلابي
and I just asked them, give me a picture, I will make you a poster.
وطلبت منهم ان يعطوني صورة و أني سأصنع لهم ملصق.
And that's how it started. And that's how, really,
وهكذا بدأت. وهكذا، فعلًا،
it's unleashed, because suddenly people
انطلقت، لأن الناس فجأه
from Facebook, friends and others,
من أصدقاء الفيس بوك والأخرون،
just understand that they can be part of it.
أدركوا أنهم يمكن لهم أن يكونوا جزءً من ذلك.
It's not just one dude making one poster,
إن الأمر لا يتعلق بشخص يصنع ملصق،
it's -- we can be part of it, so they start sending me pictures
أنه --عن قدرتنا في أن نكون جزءً من ذلك، لذلك بدأوا في إرسال لي الصور
and ask me, "Make me a poster. Post it.
و يطلبوا، "اصنع لي ملصقًأ وارسله.
Tell the Iranians we from Israel love you too."
اخبر الإيرانيين إننا في اسرائيل نحبهم ايضًا."
It became, you know, at some point it was really, really intense.
اصبح الأمر، كما تعلمون، في مرحلة ما ضخم جدًا جدًأ.
I mean, so many pictures, so I asked friends
أقصد، الكتير من الصور، لذلك طلبت من أصدقائي
to come, graphic designers most of them,
الذين أغلبهم من مصممي الجرافك، ان يأتوا
to make posters with me, because I didn't have the time.
ويصنعوا الملصقات معي، لأن ليس لدي الوقت.
It was a huge amount of pictures.
كانت كمية هائلة من الصور.
So for a few days, that's how my living room was.
هكذا كان حال حجرة معيشتي لبضعة أيام.
And we received Israeli posters, Israeli images,
وأستلمنا ملصقات اسرائيلية وصور اسرائيلية،
but also lots of comments, lots of messages from Iran.
وكذلك الكثير من التعليقات والرسائل من إيران.
And we took these messages and we made posters out of it,
وجمعنا تلك الرسائل وصنعنا منها ملصقات،
because I know people: They don't read, they see images.
أنا أعرف الناس: إنهم لا يقرئون ولكن يشاهدون الصور.
If it's an image, they may read it.
إذا كانت صورة، فربما يقرؤونها.
So here are a few of them.
وهنا بعضًا منهم.
("You are my first Israelian friend. I wish we both get rid of our idiot politicians, anyway nice to see you!")
("أنت أول صديق اسرائيلي لي. اتمني ان يتخلص كلًا منا من سياسيينا الحمقي، علي أي حال سعدت لرؤياك!")
("I love that blue. I love that star. I love that flag.") This one is really moving for me because it's the story
("أحب ذلك الأزرق. أحب تلك النجمة. أحب هذا العلم.") هذه الرسالة حركت مشاعري لأنها قصة
of a girl who has been raised in Iran
لفتاة تربت بإيران
to walk on an Israeli flag to enter her school every morning,
علي أنها تدهس علي علم اسرائيلي حتى تدخل مدرستها كل صباح،
and now that she sees the posters that we're sending,
والآن وهي تري الملصقات التي نرسلها،
she starts -- she said that she changed her mind,
بدأت -- قالت أنها غيرت رأيها،
and now she loves that blue, she loves that star,
والآن هي تحب ذلك الأزرق وتحب تلك النجمة
and she loves that flag, talking about the Israeli flag,
وتحب ذلك العلم، و التحدث عن العلم الإسرائيلي،
and she wished that we'd meet and come to visit one another,
وتمنت أن نلتقي ويزور كلًا منا الأخر،
and just a few days after I posted the first poster.
وهذا فقط بعد أيام قليلة من إرسالي لأول ملصق.
The day after,
وفي اليوم التالي،
Iranians started to respond with their own posters.
بدأ الأيرانيين في الرد بملصقاتهم الخاصة.
They have graphic designers. What? (Laughter)
ماذا؟ إن لديهم مصممين جرافيك. (ضحك)
Crazy, crazy.
جنون، جنون.
So you can see they are still shy, they don't want to show their faces,
يمكنكم أن تروا أنهم لايزالون خجوليين، إنهم لا يريدون أن يظهروا وجوههم،
but they want to spread the message.
لكنهم يريدون أن ينشروا الرسالة.
They want to respond. They want to say the same thing.
إنهم يريدون ان يتجاوبوا. يريدون ان يقولوا نفس الشيء.
So. And now it's communication.
وهكذا من هنا تكون التواصل.
It's a two-way story. It's Israelis and Iranians
انها قصة ذات اتجاهين. اسرائليين وإيرانيين
sending the same message, one to each other.
يرسلون نفس الرسالة لبعضهم البعض.
("My Israeli Friends. I don't hate you. I don't want War.")
("أصدقائي الإسرائليين. أنا لا أكرهكم. أنا لا أريد الحرب.")
This never happened before, and this is two people
لم يحدث ذلك مطلقًا قبل ذلك، وهذين الشعبين
supposed to be enemies, we're on the verge of a war,
يعتبروا أعداء، نحن علي حافة حرب،
and suddenly people on Facebook are starting to say,
وفجأه الناس علي الفيس بوك بدأوا يقولوا،
"I like this guy. I love those guys."
"أنا أحب هذا الشخص. أنا أحب هؤلاء الناس."
And it became really big at some point.
وفي مرحلة ما توسع الموضوع جدًا.
And then it became news.
وبعدها أصبح أخبار.
Because when you're seeing the Middle East, you see only the bad news.
لأنكم عندما ترون الشرق الأوسط، ترون الأخبار السيئة فقط.
And suddenly, there is something that was happening
وفجأه، أصبح هناك شيئًأ يحدث
that was good news. So the guys on the news,
هناك أخبار جيدة. مذيعو الأخبار
they say, "Okay, let's talk about this."
قالوا : "حسنًا، دعونا نناقش هذا."
And they just came, and it was so much,
وجاءوا كثيرًا،
I remember one day, Michal,
اذكر يومًا أن ميشيل،
she was talking with the journalist, and she was asking him,
كانت تتكلم مع صحفي، وسألته:
"Who's gonna see the show?"And he said, "Everybody."
"من سيشاهد البرنامج؟" وقال: "الجميع."
So she said, "Everybody in Palestine, in where? Israel?
فقالت: "الجميع أين في فلسطين؟ في اسرائيل؟
Who is everybody?""Everybody."
من هم الجميع؟" "الجميع."
They said, "Syria?" "Syria."
قالوا: "سوريا؟" "سوريا."
"Lebanon?""Lebanon."
"لبنان؟" "لبنان"
At some point, he just said, "40 million people are going to see you today.
وفي مرحلة ما، قال: "40 مليون شخص سوف يشاهدونك اليوم.
It's everybody." The Chinese.
إنهم الجميع." الصينيون.
And we were just at the beginning of the story.
وكنا فقط في بداية الأمر.
Something crazy also happened.
حدث شيء جنوني أيضًا.
Every time a country started talking about it,
في كل مرة تبدأ دولة في التحدث عن الأمر،
like Germany, America, wherever,
مثل ألمانيا وامريكا واي مكان،
a page on Facebook popped up with the same logo
تبرز صفحة علي الفيس بوك بنفس الشعار
with the same stories, so at the beginning
بنفس القصص، لذلك في البداية
we had "Iran-Loves-Israel," which is an Iranian
كان لدينا "إيران تحب اسرائيل"، وهو إيراني
sitting in Tehran, saying, "Okay, Israel loves Iran?
يسكن في طهران يقول: "حسنًا، اسرائيل تحب إيران؟
I give you Iran-Loves-Israel."
أنا أقدم ’إيران تحب اسرائيل."
You have Palestine-Loves-Israel.
أنتم لديكم "فلسطين تحب اسرائيل".
You have Lebanon that just -- a few days ago.
لديكم لبنان - منذ بضعة أيام.
And this whole list of pages on Facebook
وهذه هي قائمة لكل الصفحات علي الفيس بوك
dedicated to the same message,
المكرسة لنفس الرسالة،
to people sending their love, one to each other.
لأناس يتبادلون مشاعر الحب بين بعضهم البعض.
The moment I really understood that something was happening,
في اللحظة التي أدركت فيها أن هناك شيئًا يحدث،
a friend of mine told me,
أخبرني صديقٌ لي:
"Google the word 'Israel.'"
"ابحث في جوجل علي كلمة ’اسرائيل‘."
And those were the first images on those days
وأولئك هم أول صور في تلك الأيام
that popped up from Google
التي كانت تظهر علي جوجل
when you were typing, "Israel" or "Iran."
عندما تكتب "اسرائيل" أو "إيران".
We really changed how people see the Middle East.
نحن حقًا غيرنا الطريقة التي ينظر بها الناس علي الشرق الأوسط.
Because you're not in the Middle East.
لأنكم لستم في الشرق الأوسط.
You're somewhere over there, and then you want to see the Middle East,
أنت في مكانًا ما، وتريد أن تري الشرق الأوسط،
so you go on Google and you say, "Israel,"
لذلك تبحث علي جوجل علي مثلًا "اسرائيل"،
and they give you the bad stuff.
ويعطوك الأخبار السيئة.
And for a few days you got those images.
منذ أيام كنت تحصل علي هذه الصور.
Today the Israel-Loves-Iran page
اليوم صفحة "اسرائيل نحب إيران"
is this number, 80,831, and two million people last week
قد زارها 80,831 و مليوني شخص في الأسبوع الماضي
went on the page and shared, liked, I don't know,
ذهبوا إلي الصفحة وشاركوا وأعجبوا، وعلي ما أعلم،
commented on one of the photos.
علقوا على واحدة من الصور.
So for five months now, that's what we are doing,
خمسة أشهر الآن، وذلك ما نفعله،
me, Michal, a few of my friends, are just making images.
أنا وميشيل وبعض الأصدقاء نقوم بعمل الصور.
We're showing a new reality
نحن نعرض واقع جديد
by just making images
فقط بعمل الصور
because that's how the world perceives us.
لأن هكذا يرانا العالم.
They see images of us, and they see bad images.
يرون صورًا لنا، يرون صورًا سيئة.
So we're working on making good images. End of story.
لذلك نحن نعمل علي صناعة صور جيدة. وهذا كل شيء.
Look at this one. This is the Iran-Loves-Israel page.
انظروا إلي هذه. هذه هي صفحة "إيران تحب اسرائيل".
This is not the Israel-Loves-Iran. This is not my page.
إنها ليست "اسرائيل تحب إيران". هذه ليست صفحتي.
This is a guy in Tehran on the day of remembrance
هذا الشخص من طهران في ذكرى
of the Israeli fallen soldier
سقوط الجندي الاسرائيلي
putting an image of an Israeli soldier on his page.
يضع صورة جندي اسرائيلي علي صفحته.
This is the enemy.
هذا هو العدو.
What?
ماذا؟
("Our heartfelt condolences to the families who lost their dearests in terror attack in Bulgaria")
("تعازينا القلبية للأسر التي فقدت احبتها في الهجوم الإرهابي في بلغاريا")
And it's going both ways.
وهذا من الجانبين.
It's like, we are showing respect, one to each other.
إنه كأنما كلًا منا يظهر الأحترام للأخر.
And we're understanding. And you show compassion.
ونحن متفهمين. وأنتم تظهرون الرحمة.
And you become friends.
وتصبحون أصدقاء.
And at some point, you become friends on Facebook,
وفي مرحلة ما، تصبحون أصدقاء علي الفيس بوك،
and you become friends in life.
ثم تصبحون أصدقاء في الحياة.
You can go and travel and meet people.
وتسافرون و تقابلون أشخاص.
And I was in Munich a few weeks ago.
منذ بضعة أيام كنت في ميونخ.
I went there to open an exposition about Iran
ذهبت إلي هناك لأفتتح معرض عن إيران
and I met there with people from the page
وتقابلت هناك بأشخاص من الصفحة
that told me, "Okay, you're going to be in Europe,
وقالوا لي: "حسنًا، أنت ذاهب إلي أوربا،
I'm coming. I'm coming from France, from Holland,
أنا قادم. أنا قادم من فرنسا، من هولندا،
from Germany," of course, and from Israel people came,
من ألمانيا"، وبالطبع جاء أشخاص من اسرائيل،
and we just met there for the first time in real life.
وتقابلنا هناك لأول مرة علي أرض الواقع.
I met with people that are supposed to be my enemies
قابلت الأشخاص المفترض أنهم أعدائي
for the first time. And we just shake hands,
للمرة الأولي. وتصافحنا بالأيدي،
and have a coffee and a nice discussion,
وشربنا القهوة ودار بيننا مناقشة لطيفة،
and we talk about food and basketball.
وتحدثنا عن الطعام وكرة السلة.
And that was the end of it.
وهكذا إنتهي الأمر.
Remember that image from the beginning?
هل تذكرون الصورة التي عرضتها في البداية؟
At some point we met in real life, and we became friends.
في مرحلة ما تقابلنا في أرض الواقع، و أصبحنا أصدقاء.
And it goes the other way around.
والعكس بالعكس.
Some girl that we met on Facebook
فتاة من الذين قابلناهم علي الفيس بوك
never been in Israel, born and raised in Iran,
لم تزر اسرائيل قبلًا، وُلدت وتربت بإيران،
lives in Germany, afraid of Israelis
تعيش بألمانيا، تخاف من الاسرائليين
because of what she knows about us,
بسبب ما تعرفه عنا،
decides after a few months of talking on the Internet
قررت بعد بضعة شهور من الكلام عبر الإنترنت
with some Israelis to come to Israel,
مع بعض الاسرائليين أن تأتي لاسرائيل،
and she gets on the plane and arrives at Ben Gurion
وأخذت الطائرة ووصلت إلي بن غوريون
and says, "Okay, not that big a deal."
وقالت: "حسنًا، لم يكن ذلك صعبًا."
So a few weeks ago, the stress is getting higher,
منذ بضعة أسابيع، اخذ الضغط بالتزايد،
so we start this new campaign
لذلك بدأنا حملة جديدة
called "Not ready to die in your war."
تدعي "لست مستعد أن أموت في حربكم".
I mean, it's plus/minus the same message,
أعني أنها نفس الرسالة تقريبًا،
but we wanted really to add some aggressivity to it.
ولكننا أردنا أن نضيف إليها بعض العدوانية.
And again, something amazing happened,
ومجددًا، حدث شئٌ مذهل،
something that we didn't have on the first wave of the campaign.
شئٌ لم يحدث في الموجة الأولي للحملة،
Now people from Iran, the same ones who were shy
والآن أشخاص من إيران، هم نفسهم الذين كانوا خجولين
at the first campaign and just sent, you know,
في الحملة الأولي وأرسلوا فقط، كما تعلمون،
their foot and half their faces,
أقدامهم ونصف وجوههم،
now they're sending their faces, and they're saying,
والأن يرسلون وجوههم، وهم يقولون:
"Okay, no problem, we're into it. We are with you."
"حسنًا، لامشكلة، نحن مهتمين بها. نحن معكم."
Just read where those guys are from.
اقرءوا من أين جاءوا هؤلاء الأشخاص.
And for every guy from Israel,
ولكن فرد من اسرائيل،
you've got someone from Iran.
لديكم أخر من إيران،
Just people sending their pictures.
مجرد ناس يرسلون صورهم.
Crazy, yes?
جنون، أليس كذلك؟
So --
لذلك--
(Applause)
(تصقيق)
So you may ask yourself, who is this dude?
لذلك ربما تسألون نفسكم، من هذا الشخص؟
My name is Ronny Edry, and I'm 41, I'm an Israeli,
أنا أسمي روني إدري، عمري 41 عام، وأنا من اسرائيل،
I'm a father of two, I'm a husband,
أنا أب لطفلين، وزوج،
and I'm a graphic designer. I'm teaching graphic design.
ومصمم جرافك. أنا أُدرس تصميم الجرافك.
And I'm not that naive, because a lot of the time
وأنا لست بتلك السذاجة، لأني في غالب الوقت
I've been asked, many times I've been asked, "Yeah, but,
إني أُسئل، في كثير من مرات أُسئل، "صحيح، ولكن،
this is really naive, sending flowers over, I mean — "
أنه من الحماقة، ارسال زهور، اقصد --"
I was in the army. I was in the paratroopers for three years,
أنا كنت بالجيش. أنا كنت بسلاح المظلات لمدة 3 سنوات،
and I know how it looks from the ground.
وأعرف كيف تبدو من الأرض.
I know how it can look really bad.
أعرف أنها قد تبدو سيئة جدًا.
So to me, this is the courageous thing to do,
لذلك بالنسبة لي، إنه من الشجاعة أن تفعل ذلك،
to try to reach the other side before it's too late,
أن تحاول الوصول للطرف الأخر قبل فوات الآوان،
because when it's going to be too late, it's going to be too late.
لأنه إذا فات الآوان، فقد فات الآوان.
And sometimes war is inevitable, sometimes,
وفي بعض الأحيان لامفر من الحرب،فقط أحيانًا،
but maybe [with] effort, we can avoid it.
لكن ربما مع بذل الجهد، يمكن لنا أن نتجنبها.
Maybe as people, because especially in Israel,
وبما أننا أشخاص، لأن حاضة في اسرائيل،
we're in a democracy. We have the freedom of speech,
نحن لدينا ديمقراطية. ولدينا حرية التعبير،
and maybe that little thing can change something.
وربما ذلك الشئ الصغير يتمكن عمل تغير.
And really, we can be our own ambassadors.
وحقًا، يمكننا أن نكون سفراء أنفسنا.
We can just send a message and hope for the best.
نحن فقط نستطيع إرسال رسالة ونأمل للأفضل.
So I want to ask Michal, my wife, to come with me
لذلك أطلب من زوجتي ميشيل أن تأتي معي
on the stage just to make with you one image,
علي المسرح لعمل صورة واحدة معكم،
because it's all about images.
لأن كل شيء متعلق بالصور.
And maybe that image will help us change something.
وربما تساعدنا تلك الصورة في عمل تغير.
Just raise that. Exactly.
ارفعوا هذا فقط. بالضبط
And I'm just going to take a picture of it,
وأنا سأخذ صوره لهذا،
and I'm just going to post it on Facebook
وسأضعها علي الفيس بوك
with kind of "Israelis for peace" or something.
مع "اسرائيلين من أجل السلام" أو شيئًا من ذلك القبيل.
Oh my God.
يا إلهي.
Don't cry.
لا تبكون.
Thank you guys.
أشكركم.
(Applause)
(تصقيق)